

# ismael Abdulai

• Home: via Raffaello 13, 46019, Viadana-MN, Italy

**Website:** <a href="https://ismael-a-portfolio.netlify.app/">https://ismael-a-portfolio.netlify.app/</a>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ismael-abdulai-112165178/

**Gender:** Male **Date of birth:** 18/10/1991 **Nationality:** Ghanaian

#### **ABOUT ME**

Highly motivated individual with tremendous competence in focusing and completing assignments in the right time frame. Always and ever ready to learn new technologies and tools needed to solve problems and to help the organization achieve its goals. A well-travelled individual who has been opened to different cultures and places and willing to work with a diverse group of people. A very affable person with good interpersonal relations with colleagues and superiors.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[09/08/2021 - 15/08/2022]

### **TECHNICAL CONSULTANT**

#### GABS RESEARCH CONSULT LIMITED

City: Accra

Country: Ghana

- Created and Implemented a data pipeline to enable quick and easier analysis of data which led to massive team efficiency and overall output.
- Led the data entry team and addressed software-related problems.
- Designed data entry set-ups and wrote meaningful logic procedures for the data entry team.
- Assisted the development of business ideas for new services.
- Reported on analyzed data to understand trends in the market.
- Documented and presented results to related departments.

[18/01/2021 - 28/06/2021]

## **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN**

#### ABB LIMITED

**Country:** Italy

- Assisted in the creation and implementation of engineering solutions.
- Assisted in the creation of automated systems to improve the quality of data delivery from sales analysis.
- Communicate with clients relating to specific project design arrangements.
- Created technical documentation for the support and maintenance of software programs.

# EDUCATION AND TRAINING

[ 16/01/2017 - 04/12/2020 ]

#### MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND NETWORKING

University of Pisa and Scuola Superiore Sant'Anna <a href="https://www.unipi.it/">https://www.unipi.it/</a>

Address: Lungarno Antonio Pacinotti, 43, , 56126, Pisa PI, Italy

# [ 24/10/2012 - 30/06/2016 ] BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

University of Information Science and Technology "St. Paul the Apostle" https://uist.edu.mk/

Address: Partizanska bb, , 6000 , Ohrid, North Macedonia

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Other language(s):

#### **English**

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2 **SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2** 

#### Italian

LISTENING A2 READING B1 WRITING B1 **SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2** 

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

#### **Technical Skills**

React | Git | SQL | NodeJS APIsWeb Apps | Java | Python | Docker | Microsoft Office (Microsoft) | CLI | CI/CD Tool: Jenkins | CSS (Bootstrap, TailwindCSS) | Mongo DB | Linux | Github | Javascript